The younger brother, Ashura,
has been reincarnated in you.
(ハゴロモ)弟アシュラは
お前に転生したのだ。
My eyes can clearly see
Ashura's chakra clinging about you.
(ハゴロモ)わしの目には はっきりと
アシュラのチャクラが→
お前に寄り添うのが見える。
《ナルト : もしかして…》
I wonder if…
あまり驚かないところを見ると→
You don't seem too surprised.
お前 実は アシュラの存在を
自分の中に感じたことが→
Perhaps, you have sensed
Ashura's presence
inside you already?
あるんじゃないのか？
I thought as much.
Then you must know already…
やはり そうか。
それなら
もう わかっているはずだな。
who is the reincarnate
of the older one, Indra…
兄インドラの転生者が 誰なのかも。
サスケ…。
Sasuke…
Sasuke did that?
((シカマル : サスケが そんなことを…。
(シノ)ああ 信じられない事態だな。
Yes, it's an unbelievable situation.
(赤丸)クゥーン。
だから サスケのことは
俺に任せてほしいんだ。
That's why I want you
to let me handle Sasuke.
(テンテン)サスケを一人で やる!?
You want to take on
Sasuke alone?
そんなんで 私たちみんなが
納得できるわけないでしょ！
How can you expect us
to agree to that?
テンテンの言うとおりだ ナルト。
Tenten is right, Naruto.
お前一人のわがままには
つきあっていられない。
We can't just give in
to your stubbornness.
なぜなら これは
里の大きな問題だ。
The reason is…
this is a big problem
for the village.
これは わがままじゃねえんだ。
I'm not being stubborn.
You said you'd give us
the details when we got home,
(キバ)帰ってから
詳しく話すっつうからよ…。
何を言うかと思えば！
俺たちだって 覚悟して→
but I never thought
this is what you'd say!
We've all made up our minds
to kill Sasuke!
サスケのことを殺すって
決めたんだぞ！
Hey, Naruto, I hope you're not saying
you'll get Sasuke all by yourself,
(シカマル)おい ナルト お前 まさか
一人でやるって言っときながら→
サスケをかばう
ってんじゃねえだろうな。
when you're actually planning
to protect him.
ああ サスケをかばうなんて
そんなつもりは ねえよ。
No, I have no intention
of protecting Sasuke.
(ネジ)五影会談で
大立ち回りをやらかし→
After all the fighting
at the Five Kage Summit,
その後 ダンゾウと戦って
そこまで弱っていたサスケなら→
and fighting Danzo…
If Sasuke was so weakened
at that time,
なんで 一気に片をつけなかった？
why didn't you take him out
right then?
(サクラ)マダラも いたし！
Madara was there too!
It didn't seem like it would
be an easy task. Besides…
そんなに簡単な感じじゃなかった。
それに…。
That's no reason to let him
get away so easily!
だからってよ みすみす
逃がすことはねえだろ！
おい ナルト オメエは強ぇんだぜ。
Hey, Naruto…
You're strong.
ペイン ぶっ倒した
英雄ってヤツだろうが！
You're the hero who took
down Pain, aren't you?!
英雄？
ああ。
Hero?
Yeah. You could take Sasuke down
like you did back then.
サスケの野郎も
あん時みてぇによ！
そうじゃねえんだ。
あん？
That's not true.
(そんなんで 今のサスケは倒せねえ。
それが わかった))
I wouldn't be able to beat Sasuke
with something like that now.
That's what I found out.
《アイツの中にも…》
Inside him too, is…
そうなんだろ？
Isn't that right?
The Sage of Six Paths
(ハゴロモ)兄 インドラは
お前に転生したのだ。
The older brother, Indra,
has been reincarnated in you.
My eyes can clearly see
Indra's chakra clinging about you.
わしの目には はっきりと
インドラのチャクラが→
お前に寄り添うのが見える。
You don't seem too surprised.
あまり驚かないところを見ると→
お前 実は インドラの存在を→
Perhaps, you have sensed
Indra's presence inside you already?
自分の中に感じたことが
あるんじゃないのか？
やはり そうか。
I thought as much.
Then you must know already…
それなら もう
わかっているはずだな。
who is the reincarnate
of the younger one, Ashura…
弟 アシュラの転生者が誰なのかも。
(サスケ)ナルト…。
Naruto…
そうなんだろ？
Isn't that right?
そうだ やはり感じていたな。
Yes. You sensed it, after all.
俺や サスケの前にも→
It seems that there were
other reincarnates
その なんだ
転生者ってのがいたらしいけど→
besides Sasuke and me…
ソイツら 結局どうなったんだ？
Who were the others?
一世代前の転生者は
千手柱間と うちはマダラだった。
The first generation of reincarnates
were Hashirama Senju and Madara Uchiha.
柱間がアシュラ マダラがインドラだ。
Hashirama was Ashura.
Madara was Indra.
You know how they ended up.
その２人が
どうなったかは わかるな？
However, before Madara could end
his life as a reincarnate,
ただ マダラは 転生者を終える前に
ある問題を作ってしまった。
he created a certain problem.
Madara was so obsessed with power
that he stole some of Hashirama's.
力に とりつかれすぎたマダラは
柱間の力を奪った。
つまり それは
弟 アシュラの一部と→
Which, in short,
caused the merging
of a portion of Ashura's chakra
with Indra's chakra…
兄 インドラのチャクラを一つに
融合してしまうこととなり→
And the result was that
it became essentially, my own chakra.
わし自身のチャクラを
導き出してしまう結果となった。
そう 輪廻眼を開眼したのだ。
That's right,
he awakened the Rinnegan.
I always thought that someone
like that would appear
(ハゴロモ)インドラ…
そして インドラの転生側に→
among either Indra
or his reincarnates.
そういう輩が
いずれは出現すると思っていた。
Hence, I left behind
the stone tablet
だから わしは石碑を残し→
that contained my writings
on how to deal with this.
考えを改める導きを書き残した。
意味をなさなかったようだが。
Although, it seems no one could
understand its meaning…
So, Super Sage Gramps, you've been watching
じゃあ 仙人の大じいちゃんは→
your kids' sibling rivalry
all this time?
ずっと自分の子供の
兄弟ゲンカを見てきたってことか。
まあ そうなるな。
Yes, I suppose you could say that.
そうか…。
I see…
Through Ninshu,
忍宗において チャクラは
個々を繋げる力と説いた。
I preached that chakra is the power
that links individuals.
わしは チャクラを
個一つだけの力を→
I strongly believe that chakra
should not be something
that amplifies the strength
of one person alone.
増幅するものであっては
ならないと信じておる。
母であるカグヤは
乱世を終わらせた後も→
Even after my mother, Kaguya,
put an end to chaotic times,
she ruled with her power alone.
一人だけで 世界を束ねた。
が やがて 母の力は
うぬぼれを生み→
However, my mother's power
bred arrogance within her.
人々は その力の存在を
恐れるようになっていった。
And mankind began to dread
the existence of that power.
That is why my mother,
once known as the Rabbit Goddess,
うさぎの女神と
呼ばれていた母が→
いつしか鬼と恐れられるように
なったのも このためだ。
became feared as a demon.
力が一人に集中すれば
それは 暴走し→
When power is concentrated
in one person,
that power runs rampant and
in time, it possesses the person.
やがて 力に取りつかれてしまう。
The current Madara is
a prime example of that…
今のマダラが まさにそれだ。
まるで 母 カグヤのようだ。
He's become just like
my mother, Kaguya.
Now, he's no longer
Indra's incarnate.
インドラの転生者を終えた今は
十尾の力を得て わしに近づき→
He's obtained Ten Tails' power
and is getting close to me.
And he is trying to obtain even
my mother Kaguya's power.
母 カグヤの力にさえ
近づこうとしている。
無限月読とは
幻術にかけるだけではない。
The Infinite Tsukuyomi doesn't
just cast genjutsu over you.
幻術の夢を見せ続け 生かしたまま
個々の力を利用するために→
It keeps you trapped
inside genjutsu dreams,
so that the caster can use your
individual power while keeping you alive.
You're attached to the roots
of the Divine Tree,
皆を神樹の根に繋げて
生きた奴隷とする幻術だ。
and turned into living slaves.
Mother possessed the power
of Sharingan as well as Byakugan.
母は 白眼以外に
写輪眼をも有していた。
She used her Visual Prowess to cast
that jutsu upon the populace.
瞳力を使い その術を
民へと向けたこともある。
It was a ghastly jutsu.
凄惨な術であった。
チャクラが一つになってしまえば
また 新たなチャクラの実が出現する。
If all chakra were to
be reunited into one again,
a new Chakra Fruit
would take shape.
それだけは なんとしても
止めなければ 世界は終わる。
That must be prevented
at all costs…
or this world will end.
わしは お前に マダラを
止めてほしいと思っている。
I would like you to stop Madara.
今までの 転生者と違い
少々 バカっぽい。
Unlike the previous reincarnates,
you tend to be a little bit of a fool.
But there may be potential
in your unpredictability.
その意外性
そこに可能性があるかもしれん。
Even long after you died,
you tried to protect the world…
死んでさえ ずっと長えこと
見守ろうとしてきた世界が→
And even when
it's turned out like this,
こんなになってんのに
まだ俺たちのことを→
you still have faith in us.
Thank you.
信じてくれて ありがとう。
礼を言うな。
わしには そんな資格はない。
Don't thank me.
I don't deserve it.
今の世が インドラ…。
If the current world desires Indra's,
or rather, my mother's way…
いや 母のやり方を
本当は望んでいて→
and if that's the natural flow…
それが自然の流れだとしたら→
then I'm the one who's selfishly
trying to go against it and stop it.
わしは 自分のわがままで
止めようとしていることになる。
尾獣の使われ方にしてみても→
Even in terms of how
the Tailed Beasts are being used,
世の均衡と平和ではなく
兵器としてのみ使われる。
not for maintaining peace and balance,
but only as weapons…
わしの考えは甘いのかもしれんな。
Perhaps my way is naïve.
いや。
No!
You're not wrong, Super Gramps!
大じいちゃんは 間違ってねえよ。
そのとおりだぜ じじい！
You're absolutely right, old man!
Oh, aren't you Gaara's?
あっ… 我愛羅んとこの…
なんで 俺の中に？
Why are you inside of me?
オビトのヤツがな…。
You see, Obito…
八っつぁん!?
Octopops!
He extracted a portion of Shukaku's
and my chakra from Madara.
守鶴と俺のチャクラの一部を
マダラから引き抜いたんだ。
オメエに足りてねえ尾獣の力を→
He knew exactly which Tailed Beast
powers you were lacking, that guy!
ちゃんと
わかってやがったぜ アイツ。
オビトが…。
(九喇嘛)いろいろあってな。
Obito did that?
A lot of things happened.
わしも お前の中へ入れた。
He even put me inside of you.
(九喇嘛)これで
すべての尾獣のチャクラが→
Now you've got the chakra of all
nine Tailed Beasts within you, Naruto!
お前の中へ入ったぞ ナルト。
Even you?
The other half of Kurama?
九喇嘛の もう片方のヤツまで…。
これで やっと約束の時がきたぜ。
六道のじじいよ。
The promised time has
finally come, old man Six Paths!
そうだな 九喇嘛よ。
ガマ丸の予言どおり→
You're right, my dear Kurama…
Just as Gamamaru prophesied…
９匹の獣の名を呼び
戯れる碧眼の少年。
a blue-eyed youth who can name all
nine beasts and frolic among them.
予言って 大ガマ仙人が
エロ仙人に伝えた予言のこと？
Prophesied? You mean the prophecy
Giant Gramps Sage passed on
to the Pervy Sage?
ガマ丸ってのが本当の名前…。
Gamamaru is his real name?
そこまで知ってる
大じいちゃんてば→
You're pretty awesome because
you know that, Super Gramps!
やっぱ すげぇな！
Hey, Naruto!
おい ナルト。
えっ？
フフフフフ… お前は やはり
皆の協力を得る魅力があるようだ。
You truly have the ability
to win other's cooperation.
わしの魂を こうして呼べ
アシュラが転生したのも うなずける。
You managed to summon my soul.
And accepted that Ashura has
reincarnated inside of you.
ハハハ。
(ハゴロモ)守鶴 又旅。
Shukaku.
Matatabi.
磯撫 孫悟空 穆王。
Isobu.
Son Goku.
Kokuo.
犀犬 重明。
Saiken.
Chomei.
牛鬼 九喇嘛。
Gyuki.
Kurama.
予言の子が
世界を変えるときがきたようだ。
It seems the time has come…
for the child of prophecy
to change the world.
(ハゴロモ)ナルトよ。
My dear Naruto…
お前は何がしたい？
What do you want to do?
この戦いの果てに何を望む？
What do you seek for
the aftermath of this war?
お前の正直な考えを聞きたい。
I would like to hear
your honest thoughts and opinions.
確かに俺ってば
そのアシュラってヤツに似てっかもな。
Maybe I'm really like
this Ashura guy.
ただ ソイツと違ってバカでガキで→
Only…unlike him,
I'm just a stupid kid
いろんなこと よくわかんねえかも
しんねえけど→
who doesn't know much
about a lot of things.
仲間が
どういうもんかは知ってるよ。
But, I do know what friends are.
And I want to protect them all.
俺は それを守りてぇ。
そんだけだ。
That's it.
それが お前の答えか…。
Is that your answer?
ああ。
Yeah…
Long ago, I entrusted
everything to Ashura and
かつては
弟 アシュラにすべてを託し→
兄 インドラに目を向けてやることが
できなかった。
cast my attention away
from Indra.
それが災いのもととなった。
That proved to be
the source of calamity.
利き腕を出せ。
Put out your dominant arm.
This time, I am also entrusting
my power to you, Indra's reincarnate.
此度は 兄 インドラの
転生者である お前にも→
わしの力を託すことにした。
そして これから先 ナルトとサスケ→
From this point on,
Naruto and Sasuke…
What you both shall do,
and what shall transpire,
お前たちが どうするか
どうなるかは お前たち次第だ。
will be up to the two of you.
俺とナルトは…。
Naruto and I…
Sasuke and I…
俺とサスケは
本当の兄弟じゃねえけど→
…may not be real brothers,
仲直りは できると思うんだ。
but I really believe that
we can make peace.
俺たち かなりの友達だから。
Because we're pretty good friends.
さあ。
Now then…
(香燐)おい カブト！ サスケは？
サスケは 大丈夫なんだろうな!?
Hey, Kabuto!
Sasuke's… Sasuke's going
to be okay, right?
(香燐)おい！
なんとか言えよ！ この！
Hey, say something, you—!
あっ！
オビト！ ナルトは… ナルトは大丈夫なの？
Obito!
Is Naruto all right?
(オビト)人柱力のナルトは
尾獣を抜かれたら死ぬ。
Naruto the Jinchuriki will die if
his Tailed Beast is extracted…
But I put the Tailed Beast
back inside him.
だが 尾獣は入れた。
これで なんとかなるはずだ。
He should be okay now.
う…。
あっ！
サスケ！
Sasuke!
ナルト…。
Naruto!
(ナルト/サスケ)いくか。
– Time to go.
(マダラ)柱間以来だ このワクワクは。
You're the first since Hashirama
to make me feel this excited!
まだ踊れるだろ。
更に別の技はないのか？
Can you still dance?
Do you have any other techniques?
Give me some more fun!
もっと楽しませてくれ。
This guy…even after
a barrage of Sekizo…!
《ガイ : コイツ 連続の夕象を…》
Guy Sensei!
(リー)ガイ先生！
(我愛羅)あれでも ダメなのか…。
Even that…didn't work…
(カカシ)ハァ ハァ…。
ハァ ハァ…。
《夕象では ダメか…》
Sekizo…isn't enough!
ハハハッ いいぞ もっと踊れ。
This is great!
Keep on dancing!
《もう 夜ガイしかない…》
All that's left…is Night Guy!
Given the state of
his heart's Chakra Point,
心臓の点穴からみても
次が最後の攻撃となるな。
this will be his final attack…
積！
Charge!
あの構え 夕象じゃない！
That stance is not the Sekizo!
Don't tell me he has something
even greater!
まさか あれ以上の
技があるというのか…。
ガイ…。
Guy!
Come on, Dad, hurry!
((ほら 父さん急いで。
(サクモ)慌てなくても
アカデミーは逃げやしないだろう？
There's no need to rush.
The Academy isn't going
to run away, is it?
入学手続きの時間は
決まってるんだよ。
There's a set time for
entrance applications.
あっ はじめまして。
Oh, nice to meet you!
うちの子が これから
アカデミ-でお世話になります。
My son will be attending
the Academy.
父さん！
Dad…
仲よくしてやってくださいね。
I hope those two
will get along okay.
(ダイ)いや それは無理ですな。
I'm afraid that will
be impossible!
えっ えっ？ そんな…。
Huh? What a thing to say!
まさか モンスターペアレント？
Are you one of
those monster parents?!
いや 父さん違うんだよ。
No, Dad… You're wrong.
今回 コイツは
アカデミー試験に落ちたの。
He failed the Academy
entrance exam.
あっ… そ それは 失礼しました。
Oh, pardon me! I just assumed
since you were in front of the Academy.
アカデミーの前だったので つい…。
ハハハハハッ！
そういうわけなんですよ。
Don't worry about it!
そこ 笑うとこなの？
Uh, I don't think it's anything
to be laughing about.
こらっ カカシ！ 失礼だぞ。
Hey, Kakashi, don't be rude.
父さんのほうが もう
失礼かましちゃってるでしょ。
But Dad, you were a lot ruder
just a minute ago.
だいたいコイツは
忍者アカデミーに入ろうとしてんのに→
I mean, this guy is trying
to get in to the Academy
忍術 使えないみたいだし
どう考えたって…。
even though he can't
use ninjutsu.
っと… そろそろ行かないと
時間に遅れちゃうよ 父さん。
Oops, we should get going,
or we're going to be late.
あ ああ。
Right.
では…。
Excuse me.
はたけカカシだったな？
Your name's Kakashi Hatake, right?
ん？
応援ありがとう！
Thank you for your support!
は？
カカシ。
Kakashi…
Don't slack off just because
you got into the Academy.
アカデミー入学が決まったからって→
うかうかしてられないよ。
え？
このままいくと
あの子は お前より強くなる。
At the rate he's training,
that boy will become
stronger than you.
アイツが？
He will?
補欠の発表は まだだろう？
They haven't announced
the alternates yet, have they?
アカデミーもバカじゃない。
The Academy isn't dumb.
You should ask what his name is
and remember it.
彼の名前を聞いて
覚えておくといい。
え～！
What…?
いいライバルになるよ。
He'll be a good rival for you.
おい お前！
Hey, you!
名前は？
What's your name?
マイト・ガイ！
Might Guy!
(これから
誰よりも強くなる男だ！))
((今回ばかりは
いいときに来てくれたよ。
(大丈夫か？ カカシ))
《本当に 父さんの
言ったとおりだったよ…。
ガイ！》
このチャクラ 認めてやろう。
体術において 俺の戦った者で→
お前の右に出る者は
１人としておらん。
このマダラが
お前を最強と呼んでやる！
流！
《速い！
なに 空間がねじ曲がっただと!?》
夜ガイ！
うわっ！
ガイ先生…。
《これが ガイの最後の技。
どうなった？》
ハァ ハァ…。
ハハハッ
死ぬところだったぜ こやつめ。
風前の灯火だが
楽しませてくれた 礼だ。
灰になる前に→
俺が殺してやる！
《求道玉を蹴るだと!?》
ゲキマユ先生…。
(マダラ)ナルト…。
いや なんとなく前とは違うな。
《オビトのヤツが…》
あぁ。
自分でも不思議に思うってばよ。
今なら全部を変えられそうだ！
オープニングは にぎやかに→
夏のお祭り気分とまいりましょう。
『大東京音頭』。
皆さん お手拍子 お願いします。